Hi I'm Tim Gipson with some tips on bathroom plumbing.
Now bathroom plumbing has three basic components.
You have your hot and cold water supply, you have your drain, and your vent system.
Now with the drain and the vent system those work together.
And the drain lines actually go from your lavatories, your shower drain, tub drain, and your toilet.
And go down to the sewer lines.
But with those drain lines are actually vent lines that are connected and go up through your walls, out through your ceiling, and to a roof vent.
Without those vent lines the water when it would try to drain would actually create a suction, and you wouldn't be able to get any drain at all.
Now with your drain lines, when those are installed, we have what we call a trap.
And what this is, it's a one hundred and eighty degree shaped fitting that attaches the drain line and stands between it and your wall.
What that trap does is actually it just traps some water in there.
And what this allows is it allows to cut any kind of waste odor that may come out of your sinks.
So if you have some strange odors coming out of either your shower drain or tub drain or your lavatory drains, then you might want to check and make sure that you have a trap installed.
Because that water just makes a barrier.
And that is the basic components.
Then you look at your faucets.
You have different type of faucets.
In this case we have a single handle faucet, you can have dual faucets, and there are variant type of faucets that you can get.
And that can add a different type of style to your bathroom.
So I'm Tim Gipson with some tips on bathroom plumbing.